[
    {
        "question": "Native Americans diversified into a variety of different tribes over the course of thousands of years as the Ice Age came to an end. This climactic of North America helped also to create the various North American climates and regions.",
        "choice": {
            "A": "Regionalization", 
            "B": "Renunciation", 
            "C": "Rehabilitation", 
            "D": "Reaction", 
            "E": "Randomization"
        },
        "answer": "Regionalization"
    },
    { 
        "question": "The discovery of in the late 1990s has changed the history of early American settlement from a viewpoint that suggested that there was one major migration of Asians to North America via an 'ice free corridor,' to one that suggests that several different migrations took place over the course of thousands of years.",
        "choice": {
            "A": "Spirit Cave Man", 
            "B": "Chadwick Man", 
            "C": "Kennewick Man", 
            "D": "Monte Verde Man", 
            "E": "Batman"
        },
        "answer": "Kennewick Man"
    },
    { 
        "question": "Prior to the arrival of Europeans, the Americas were like a Garden of Eden, where the native peoples lived in peace and harmony with one another.",
        "choice": {
            "A": "True", 
            "B": "False"
        },
        "answer": "False"
    },
    { 
        "question": "The Revolution changed the living patterns of hunters and gatherers, leading them to settle down and eventually develop villages, then towns and eventually cities. This process is important in the formation of civilization.",
        "choice": {
            "A": "Industrial",
            "B": "American",
            "C": "Climate", 
            "D": "Agricultural",
            "E": "Urban"
        },
        "answer": "Agricultural"
    },
    { 
        "question": "The first generation of Europeans to explore North America were looking for...",
        "choice": {
            "A": "A navigable route to India and China", 
            "B": "Gold", 
            "C": "Fame and fortune",
            "D": "Lands to conquer", 
            "E": "All of the above"
        },
        "answer": "All of the above"
    },

    { 
        "question": "According to an essay written by. _____ the native population of the Indies were decimated by disease and the brutal treatment of Europeans during the early 1500s.",
        "choice": {
            "A": "Juan Rodriguez de Santiago", 
            "B": "Bartolomé de Las Casas",
            "C": "Alvar Nuñez Cabeza de Vaca", 
            "D": "Hildebrando Villareal", 
            "E": "Jose Guillermo de La Enchilada Muy Caliente"
        },
        "answer": "Bartolomé de Las Casas"
    },
    { 
        "question": "Spanish ____ traveled extensively through the American South and South West during the early and mid 1500s in search of \"El Dorado,\" or cities of gold where they believed they could find immense wealth and fame.",
        "choice": {
            "A": "Friars", 
            "B": "Seadogs", 
            "C": "Conquistadors", 
            "D": "Tourists", 
            "E": "Functionaries"
        },
        "answer": "Conquistadors"
    },
    { 
        "question": "The myth of 'El Dorado' was spread far and wide because of the exploits of men like Francisco Pizarro who conquered the Inca in Peru and ____ who brought down the Aztecs in central Mexico, both of whom became fantastically rich and powerful in the process.",
        "choice": {
            "A": "Juan Rodriguez Cabrillo", 
            "B": "Gabriel García Márquez",
            "C": "Jose Martí", 
            "D": "Hernán Cortés",
            "E": "Hernando de Soto"
        },
        "answer": "Hernán Cortés"
    },
    { 
        "question": "The defeat of the Aztec Empire in central Mexico was possible because...",
        "choice": {
            "A": "The Spanish were aided by thousands of other Indian tribesmen who despised the Aztecs", 
            "B": "Smallpox killed a few of the Aztecs", 
            "C": "The Spanish were able to communicate with various Indians through the aid of a young woman named Chelada", 
            "D": "Cortéz had signed a contract with the governor of Cuba to conquer the Aztecs", 
            "E": "All of the above"
        },
        "answer": "All of the above"
    },
    { 
        "question": "The destruction of the Spanish Armada in 1588 helped expand their influence and power into North America.",
        "choice": {
            "A": "Germany", 
            "B": "England", 
            "C": "Italy", 
            "D": "Russia", 
            "E": "France"
        },
        "answer": "England"
    },
    { 
        "question": "The first attempted settlement in North America, the colony at was a failure since the people who moved there mysteriously disappeared never to be seen alive again.",
        "choice": {
            "A": "Jamestown", 
            "B": "Plymouth", 
            "C": "New Amsterdam",
            "D": "Massachusetts Bay", 
            "E": "Roanoke"
        },
        "answer": "Roanoke"
    },
    { 
        "question": "According to ____ in Virginia, 'The mildness of the air, fertility of the Soil, and the situation of the rivers are propitious to the nature and use of man as no place is more convenient for pleasure, profit, and man's sustenance.'",
        "choice": {
            "A": "Sir Walter Raleigh", 
            "B": "Sir Francis Drake", 
            "C": "Captain John Smith", 
            "D": "Captain Benjamin Sisko", 
            "E": "Captain James T. Kirk"
        },
        "answer": "Captain John Smith"
    },
    { 
        "question": "Life in Jamestown, Virginia was generally very easy for the first settlers that arrived in 1607.",
        "choice": {
            "A": "True", 
            "B": "False"
        },
        "answer": "False"
    },
    { 
        "question": "Most of the poor Englishmen and women who arrived in the English colonies of North America prior to the 1750s were",
        "choice": {
            "A": "Slaves", 
            "B": "Aristocrats", 
            "C": "Acrobats",
            "D": "Free peasants", 
            "E": "Indentured Servants"
        },
        "answer": "Indentured Servants"
    },
    { 
        "question": "The is name given to the journey that West Africans were forced to endure on slave ships from Africa to the Americas.",
        "choice": {
            "A": "Atlantic Crossing",
            "B": "Mid-Atlantic Passage", 
            "C": "Middle Passage",
            "D": "Crossing", 
            "E": "Terrible Travel"
        },
        "answer": "Middle Passage"
    },
    { 
        "question": "Once slaves arrived in the New World they were forced to endure a process called __, in which they were given new names, made to learn European languages, and generally learn the routines of slave life.",
        "choice": {
            "A": "The Training",
            "B": "The Terrible Transformation", 
            "C": "Seasoning",
            "D": "Assimilation", 
            "E": "Conversion"
        },
        "answer": "Seasoning"
    },
    { 
        "question": "The first Africans that arrived in Jamestown were treated as",
        "choice": {
            "A": "Slaves", 
            "B": "Indentured Servants",
            "C": "Non-Incorporated Commodities", 
            "D": "Freemen", 
            "E": "None of the above"
        },
        "answer": "Indentured Servants"
    },
    { 
        "question": "The life of in mid 17th century Virginia is proof that race relations in early Virginia did not have to develop into a pattern of racebased slavery.",
        "choice": {
            "A": "Andrew Johnson",
            "B": "Anthony Johnson", 
            "C": "William Swain", 
            "D": "Samuel Checkly", 
            "E": "Francis Townsend"
        },
        "answer": "Andrew Johnson"
    },
    { 
        "question": "A 1676 indentured servant and slave revolt called helped to make slavery preferable to indentured servitude for many colonists seeking workers.",
        "choice": {
            "A": "Nathaniel's Insurrection", 
            "B": "Gabriel's Mission",
            "C": "The Pequot War",
            "D": "Bacon's Rebellion",
            "E": "The Whiskey Rebellion"
        },
        "answer": "Bacon's Rebellion"
    },
    { 
        "question": "The ____ were the first English settlers to arrive in New England in 1620. They were later followed by large numbers of Puritans who were also seeking to find some religious freedom.",
        "choice": {
            "A": "Lutherans",
            "B": "Calvinists", 
            "C": "Pilgrims",
            "D": "Unitarians", 
            "E": "Presbyterians"
        },
        "answer": "Pilgrims"
    },
    { 
        "question": "Puritans believed very strongly in the Calvinist idea of which told them that God had already decided who was to be saved and who was damned to suffer in Hell. This philosophy helped to shape their lifestyle into a rigorous and serious one.",
        "choice": {
            "A": "Evangelism", 
            "B": "Idealism", 
            "C": "Puritanism", 
            "D": "Predestination", 
            "E": "Flatulence"
        },
        "answer": "Predestination"
    },
    { 
        "question": "By the late 1600s Puritan society had been undergoing some changes as the younger generation began to question the strictness of their everyday lives.",
        "choice": {
            "A": "True",
            "B": "False"
        },
        "answer": "True"
    },
    { 
        "question": "During the early 1690s the social pressures brought on by the economic, political and religious changes that were taking place convinced many New Englanders that - were the cause of all their problems.",
        "choice": {
            "A": "Indians", 
            "B": "Slaves", 
            "C": "Witches", 
            "D": "Church leaders", 
            "E": "Spirits"
        },
        "answer": "Church leaders"
    },
    { 
        "question": "According to John Locke, every person was born with natural rights including access to life, liberty and property.",
        "choice": {
            "A": "True", 
            "B": "False"
        },
        "answer": "False"
    }
]